Over here, over here! Hurry up!
A stepsister is essentially
a stranger.
Thursday, July 16th
We simply became siblings one day
because our parents suddenly
decided to get married.
We don't have the sense of kinship
that a genetic connection provides,
nor do we have any shared
experience living together.
It's not complicated.
We're obviously strangers.
It's just that...
Now that it's been a month since
Dad and Akiko-san got married
and the four of us, including
her daughter, began living together,
I'm starting to realize that my
stepsister, this "stranger,"
actually occupies a much
more ambiguous position.
She's a stranger I share a home with now.
I think it's probably fair to call her that.
But then, when I ask myself
what our relationship is...
I'm at a loss for an answer.
Oh. I'm back, Ayase-san.
Tutor me in modern lit.
Modern Lit
Huh?
Asamura
Ayase
What was your score?
I got a 38.
Wow, that's pretty impressive.
I had a feeling that's how it would go.
Episode 4 "Tendencies and Strategies"
I've never been very good at lit,
so I expected to fail this time, too.
Even though you get high
scores in other subjects?
I can never really understand how
the characters feel and all that stuff.
That's not what I was expecting.
You seem the especially considerate type.
Does it look that way to you?
Yeah. At least with me,
you try to understand my position,
and then compromise so we can get along.
You've got it backwards, Asamura-kun.
Backwards?
We have to compromise exactly because
we can't understand others' feelings.
You might have a point.
But honestly, my grade this time
could be a real problem.
If I don't pass the retest,
I'll be forced to take make-up
lessons during summer break.
I can see why you'd want to avoid that.
And I wanted to work over summer vacation...
Sorry. Not finding you a
well-paying job is on me.
Oh, no... I'm not blaming you or anything.
In fact, I feel bad for taking advantage of you.
If it's okay with you,
I'd be happy to help you study modern lit.
Thanks.
You do all right with the
essay questions at the start.
But your answers for the book questions
at the end are full of blanks.
Do you struggle with the novels so
much that you just ran out of time?
You sound like you were
watching over my shoulder.
Well, am I wrong?
No. Bullseye.
But it kind of stings that you
pinpointed my weakness so easily.
Not exactly a great feeling.
Sorry. I should have put it more gently.
I forgive you.
Also, I know you're just being blunt
because you're seriously trying to help me.
I shouldn't get pissed over it. Sorry.
It's okay. I guess that makes us even.
So it looks like you struggled the
most with the part about Sanshiro.
Yeah.
Natsume Soseki's Sanshiro is all about
the challenge of falling in love freely.
I think people today understand
some parts of the story better
than people did when the book was written.
Really? Which parts?
Actually, this might go faster if you tell me
which aspects of it were hardest for you.
Um... I don't understand what Sanshiro
is thinking, or what Mineko is thinking,
or their motives for any of
the choices they both make.
Um... You get that Sanshiro
has fallen for Mineko, right?
He has?
Fallen for, as in... he likes her
in a romantic way, right?
Yeah. Remember, he gets jealous
when other men approach her.
Isn't it kind of obvious?
He's jealous?
You mean he doesn't like it
when Mineko talks to other men?
But he doesn't tell her to stop, does he?
If he hates it so much, he should say so.
Well, maybe it's too psychologically
challenging for him
to be so direct with the person he likes.
Honestly, I don't get people who hide their
true feelings and don't say what they mean.
Okay, can you imagine a situation where
you couldn't express your true feelings?
Maybe like the first time you fell in love?
The first time I fell in love?
Have you ever been so head over heels that
you couldn't make the right decisions?
No. I have zero experience with love.
I see.
Do you, Asamura-kun?
Now that you mention it, no.
Hmm, so you don't...
That a problem?
Not really. But if neither
of us has ever been in love,
then it's probably safe to assume our lit
grades have nothing to do with experience.
You're right.
So maybe let's stop trying to
empathize with the characters.
If we can't relate to them,
then fine. That's that.
So we just take shots in the dark, then?
Not exactly. Maybe think of it
as a math formula or a puzzle.
A puzzle?
You get good grades in history, right?
Well, yeah. It's just memorization.
Yeah, exactly. It might be easier
to understand modern literature
if you can remember the historical
context of when the book was written.
Since you're good at history,
try linking that knowledge to the story,
and maybe you'll understand it better.
You're right. That might be easier for me.
Let's try practicing. There are only
a few different types of questions.
I think you can prepare
for them all by the retest.
Do you think I'll pass the retest?
I know you will, Ayase-san.
Okay. I'll do my best.
Yeah. This last one is correct,
too. I'm impressed.
I knew you could do it.
Now if you just master the novels
that will likely be covered,
the retake should be a breeze.
Thank you. You're a really good teacher.
Oh, I doubt that.
Are you smiling?
Who knows? Can't say for sure.
Sanshiro
Natsume Soseki
Friday, July 17th
Morning, Ayase-san.
Morning, Asamura-kun.
Oh, I'm good today.
I'll just grab toast or something.
What? Why?
You need to focus on studying, right?
But I promised...
As your instructor,
I want you to pass the retest.
So I'd prefer it if you concentrated
on your studies today.
Thanks.
Then I'll do just that.
You're welcome. But it's not like
you owe me anything for this.
Okay. Got it.
I'll buy you a drink, so gimme 1,000 yen!
Huh?
efficient study techniques
The 20 Most Efficient Study Methods:
Even You-Know-Who Has Used These
Powerful Secrets to Produce Results
What do you need to study more efficiently?
Recommended techniques explained simply
Introducing More Efficient Study Habits:
What's the best way to study?
How to fix your bad study habits
Up Your Efficiency with This Infallible Study Method:
The key to super efficient studying
is doing this one trick every day
Reevaluate your studying. Fix your bad habits
and win with more efficient study techniques!
A surefire win! Master this powerful technique
to increase your efficiency. Upgrade your study
balance and prepare yourself for a liberal arts
university education
Which Methods Are Wrong?
Review your study methods to improve
your efficiency
Big Brother!
Oh, it's you, Narasaka-san.
Sniff, sniff! You carry the scent of the
Asamura family yet again today.
Hey, Narasaka-san, you're kinda close.
We are close, Big Brother!
Would you quit calling me that at school?
We're just bonding, Big Bro!
Right, Broski? Big Brudder? Brother Dearest!
What's with all the variations?
I just wasn't sure which one would stick best.
You sure are spirited today.
Yeah, because I'm all done with exams!
And now I'm gonna release
all that pent-up stress at once!
So you don't have to take any retests?
Nope. I've never failed a test before.
My combined score on all
nine tests was 808 points!
How's that?!
Wow, eight hundred... Huh?!
What? That surprised you?
I bet you thought I couldn't do it!
Sorry, but no, I actually didn't.
That's so mean! I'm at the
top of my class, you know!
I've kept nearly a 90% average
all throughout high school!
Okay, since you're such
an excellent student,
I'd like to ask you something.
Yes? Don't be shy, son.
Aha.
So you're looking for a way to help
Saki study more efficiently, eh?
It feels like you're implying something.
No, no. You just seem like a devoted brother.
I helped her study, but Ayase-san
is pretty smart to begin with,
so I figure once she gets the hang of it,
she won't need my help anymore.
Yeah, that does sound like Saki.
That's why I was wondering if there's
any other way I can help her out.
Okay.
But I really don't do anything
special in particular.
I do listen to background music
when working, though.
That actually might help. Do you
have any recommended genres?
Nope!
Huh?
I just listen to whatever the app recommends.
Searching for myself is a pain!
Oh, okay.
But you know, Asamura-kun,
you really are a good brother.
You should hold your head high!
I don't think this makes me a good brother.
Personally, I think cooking for my little
brothers qualifies me as a great sister.
You have brothers?
I sure do! Tons of them!
Must be a really big family.
Yeah, about a hundred of us.
Huh?
Just kidding! It's a much more
reasonable number.
So how many, then?
You seem down, my sweet junior.
Well, more customers on the weekend
means more annoying customers to deal with.
Hold it right there. How could you talk
about our dear customers that way?
Don't you usually complain about
that a whole lot more than I do?
Whatever do you mean?
Shh.
See you later.
You really don't show people
your true colors, do you?
I got tired of everyone
getting sick of me at college.
Rewards Points Promotion
Earn up to 30%
You're the only one who knows every part of me.
Quit making it sound weird.
Restock
Take care of holds
Clean up the back room
All I did was state the naked truth!
I'm going to head ho—
You look melted.
Of course I'm melted!
The store is so crowded that
the AC isn't having any effect,
and I keep having to bend over
to carry all these heavy books.
It's doing a number on my back!
Oh, it isn't that bad.
At my age, the soreness won't hit for
two days, and by then I'll have a stiff neck,
palpitations, and shortness of breath.
Will you nurse me back to health, young man?
I'm going home.
Sob, sob...
Now that you're with that floozy,
you're just going to toss me aside?!
Why can't you be nice to me?
I'm going to have to eat here
all by my lonesome.
Stay and tell me of your adventures
with your darling little sister!
Well, I don't have any adventures to share,
but can I ask you for some advice instead?
Oh, now that does sound like
an interesting proposal!
So you want to help your sister
learn to study more efficiently? I see.
And you've been looking into
background music, have you?
Yeah. But I still can't really
pin down the best genres for it.
Yes, yes. I see.
I might have a recommendation for you.
Let's see... Which one?
Oh, here it is.
I also wanted background music to work to,
so I spent some time looking into it.
Huh.
Here, my sweet junior.
Huh?
You want to hear it in high quality, right?
Uh, yeah. I guess so.
All right, I'll play it.
Okay.
S H I B U Y A   C E N T E R
This is really great.
I thought you could try using it as
background music when you study.
Thanks. I'm surprised you
listen to music like this.
I actually just discovered it.
My senpai at work introduced me to it.
Oh, the same one, right?
The beautiful older girl
with encyclopedic knowledge?
Well... yeah.
It wouldn't be an exaggeration to say I get
most of my recommendations from her.
You two must be close.
Well, we get a lot of shifts together.
Ayase-san?
Huh? Oh, it's nothing.
I just got lost in the music for a second.
I see.
So your senpai even has
good taste in music, huh?
Yeah, but personality-wise,
she's kind of an airhead,
though in a really humorous way.
Either way, she sounds interesting.
Yeah, that I can guarantee.
Asamura-kun?
I really think that I keep taking
too much from you, Ayase-san.
I know this wasn't much,
but I hope it returns the favor a little.
Thanks. I'll try listening to it tonight.
Okay.
Oh, just leave it there.
I'll take care of the dishes.
Okay. Thanks.
Goodnight, Asamura-kun.
Yeah. Goodnight, Ayase-san.
Episode 5 "A Late Show and theReal Deal"